export interface Question {
  question: string;
  options: string[];
  correctAnswer: string;
}

export const questions: Question[] = [
  {
    question:
      'What period saw a significant population shift due to the resolution of the Dagohoy Rebellion, leading to the establishment of a new administrative center under Fray Tomas and Serafino Pongase?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Spanish Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period saw a devastating event where troops arrived and announced their intention to burn Balilihan to the ground, leaving only the belfry standing?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'American Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period involved forced displacement, fear, and targeting of civilians suspected of supporting resistance efforts?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Japanese Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      "What period saw the initial town center's failure due to water scarcity, resulting in a relocation to a more suitable location with springs like Tan Pero and Abaca?",
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Spanish Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      "What period of occupation saw a new seat of government established and appointed by Friar Tomas, the town's first leader Serafin Pongase, who later faced a tragic end?",
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Spanish Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      "What period saw the Women's Auxiliary Service (WAS), led by figures like Lutgarda Diez and Teofila A. Racho, providing crucial aid to those in need?",
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Japanese Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period introduced a new system of governance, empowering communities to elect their leaders, such as Manuel Diamante?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'American Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period saw the construction of a significant landmark, the belfry, atop Mt. Carmel Hill using materials transported from Baclayon, showcasing dedication and effort?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Spanish Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period brought intense hardship, loss of life, and destruction, leaving lasting impacts on the community?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'Japanese Occupation',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What period of occupation saw a significant rebuilding and infrastructure development following a destructive event, signifying a period of recovery and progress?',
    options: ['Spanish Occupation', 'American Occupation', 'Japanese Occupation'],
    correctAnswer: 'American Occupation',
  },
];
